# Panagiotis Simakis

Curriculum Vitae

Athens, Greece

#### SUMMARY

Software Engineer with more than 5 years of working experience in the field of Software Development, Data Science, Data Engineering & MLOps. Has worked in various sectors from Digital Marketing to e-Commerce. Loves to work with Modern Data Stacks and productize Machine Learning Systems. He usually contributes to FOSS projects during the night.

#### EXPERIENCE

Netdata Remote

• Senior Data Engineer

Oct. 2021 - Aug. 2022

Development, maintenance and monitoring of ETL pipelines for BI purposes using Apache Airflow, Cloud Functions and BigQuery. Implementation of Data Lineages (for data observability purposes) using DataHub. Introduction of great\_expectation for data validation and sanity checks. Ingestion ETL pipelines using third-party API services.

Technologies: GCP, BigQuery, Cloud Functions, Apache Airflow, DataHub, Github, Docker, Terraform, great\_expectations

Convert Group

• Data Engineer

Athens, Greece
May 2020 - Sep. 2021

Development of ETL pipelines and data automation pipelines. Deployment of Machine Learning models into production. Contribution on back-end development of eRetail Content platform.

Technologies: Prefect, AWS, Django/REST, Docker, PostgreSQL, Amazon Redshift, Celery, MLflow, Terraform

XPLAIN Athens, Greece

• Data Scientist

Feb. 2017 - Apr. 2020

Data and Text Mining using state-of-the-art and disruptive methods. Design and development of distributed web crawlers. Database administration and optimization. Implementation of workflow pipelines. Deployment of ML models to production as RESTfull API services.

**Technologies:** Python, MySQL, Celery, Docker Swarm, ELK, spaCy, NumPy/pandas

Sociality
Web Developer - Intern

Athens, Greece

Feb. 2016 - Jun. 2016

Web development using WordPress. Implementation of WordPress plugins for Woocommerce. Development of custom functionalities for WordPress.

**Technologies:** WordPress, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Shell, SQL, PHP
- Databases & Data Warehouses: MySQL, Redis, PostgreSQL, Elastic Stack, BigQuery
- Data & ML Workflow Platforms: Prefect, MLflow, Apache Airflow, great\_expectations
- Data Science & NLP:: pandas/NumPy, scikit-learn, Keras, spaCy
- Web Scraping: lxml, Selenium, Scrapy, Beautiful Soup
- Web Frameworks: Django/REST, FastAPI
- Version Control Systems & Platforms: Git, Github, Bitbucket
- Cloud Computing: AWS, GCP

# **EDUCATION**

### Department of Computer Engineering & Informatics, University of Patras

Patras, Greece

• Diploma (equivalent to B.Eng + M.Eng); GPA: 6.87

Sep. 2010 - Feb. 2017

**Thesis:** Design and Implementation of a Methodology for the Automatic Identification of the User Geographic Idiom in a Social Media Text Corpus. supervisor: Megalooikonomou Vasileios, grade: 10/10

#### LANGUAGES

• Greek: Native

English: ProficientFrench: Elementary

Certificate of Proficiency in English, The University of Mishigan

Delf A2

# CERTIFICATIONS & CONFERENCES

• Astronomer Certification for Apache Airflow Fundamentals: link	Apr. 2022
Apache Pulsar Fundamentals: link	Jan. 2022
• Open Source Software Development, Linux and Git Specialization: link	Jan. 2022
• Architecting with Google Kubernetes Engine Specialization: link	Dec. 2021
• AWS Fundamentals Specialization: link	Nov. 2020
• $O\pi e \setminus n$ conference: link	Mar. 2019
• 4th & 10th Conference of FOSS: Patras, Greece & Athens, Greece	2011, 2017
the full list	

# **PUBLICATIONS**

- Simaki, V., Simakis, P., Paradis, C., & Kerren, A. (2018). Detection of StanceRelated Characteristics in Social Media Text. In SETN '18: 10th Hellenic Conference on Artificial Intelligence New York: Association for Computing Machinery, Inc. DOI: 10.1145/3200947.3201017
- Simaki, V., **Simakis**, **P.**, Paradis, C, & Kerren, A. (2017). Identifying the Authors' National Variety of English in Social Media Text. In Proceedings of RANLP 2017 Recent Advances in Natural Language, ACL Anthology (in press)

#### Interests

GNU/Linux, MLOps, NLP, F/OSS

# ACTIVITIES

Photography, Traveling, Hiking, Sailing